

David Williams

Software Engineer



Summary

 Multi-talented Software Developer with a strong creative background. With skills in Graphic Design and a strong Entertainment-based Event Management history, I have ample experience working with a team. I offer an artistic mind attuned to making ideas come to life.



Work Experience

2018-12 -2018-12

Full Stack Web Developer

Creative Freedom Co.

- Strategized product design with UX/UI team and developed front-end code for mobile-responsive web application.
- Communicated directly with client to establish project criteria and application features, and maintained regular updates during development cycle.
- Used AJAX calls through Axios to populate user information on the frontend.
- Workflow tools included: Visual Studio Code, PyCharm, HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, Python, React, and Git.

2018-08 -2019-01

Software Engineering Fellow

General Assembly

- Completed the Software Engineering immersive and accelerated style course in a 12-week, Full-time, 800+ hour period.
- Worked individually and in group settings to complete projects designed by industry experts focused on multiple programming languages, libraries, and frameworks within 12 to 24-hour time-frames.
- Quickly grasped the fundamentals of front-end and back-end development while learning to leverage tools such as Git/GitHub, HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Node, APIs and designed/developed multiple projects focused on real-world applications.
- Provided leadership, encouragement, and support to classmates including but not limited to assisting with organization, time management, professional development and emotional support as needed

2018-05 -2018-06

Freelance Graphic Designer

Dunwoody Convention and Visitors Bureau

- Approached by the Dunwoody CVB for a logo design project in association with their 7th Annual Dunwoody Restaurant Week
- Consulted with CVB team to identify and establish needs for an animated logo
- Fulfilled client's desire to animate their pre-existing static logo in a 4-week deadline
- Provided several rounds of editing to attain client satisfaction; adjusted color settings and file size
- Packaged and delivered the logo to client for easy use in future video marketing



Education

2018

General Assembly, Software Engineering Immersive

2018

Per Scholas, CodeBridge Web Development Course

2010-08 -2015-05 Georgia State University, Psychology, Philosophy, B.S Psychology



Address

Atlanta, GA

Phone

678-886-7503

E-mail

davidwms92@gmail.com

GitHub

https://github.com/Dj-Williams

Portfolio Site

https://dj-williams.github.io/

LinkedIn

https://www.linkedin.com/in/david-williams-10272a47/



Languages:

HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, and Python

Libraries:

React, Express, MongoDB, Mongoose, SQL, Node.JS, Django, Bootstrap, JQuery, Handlebars, p5.js, Materialize

Software:

Adobe Creative Suite, GIMP 2, Visual Studio Code, PyCharm, Compass, Postman, Git



2019-06

AWS Wordpress Test Site

Pirate Labs Interview (Technical Test)

- Created a Wordpress installation from scratch utilizing Amazon Web Services
- Technologies Used: EC2, MySQL,
 Nginx, PHP, GNU Nano, VIM Editor,
 and Wordpress
- Provided SSH access to the server for task completion review
- Link: http://schooner.dnsabr.com/